Guide to the Myron S. Falk Papers 1867-1950 MS 3047
New-York Historical Society
- Series VII. Film, 1920s-1950s; 4 Linear feet
  - #6 / New #4 (Offsite-box 11, Reel -)
    Original handwriting on bottom of can: "2nd Godwin, Naumberg, Parties [word?]" Original tape around can is difficult to read, but includes the following words, among others: summer, Grandma & children in garden, Godwin, Eleanor. Modern tape: "1926, football, Godwin Co Picnic, family w/dogs" and "1926 Godwin Co Picnic."
  - #8 / New #5 (Offsite-box 11, Reel -)
    On bottom of can: '28. Modern tape: "1928: swimming, golf, dog play, Army vs. Yale game" and "1928: swim/golf."
  - #7 / New #6 (Offsite-box 11, Reel -)
    On bottom of can: "circa 1927." No other subject information.
  - #1 / New #7 (Offsite-box 11, Reel -)
    Modern tape: "Portchester in the 20s! Lots of the 3 kids, golf swings, an Isadora Duncan like dance, Perhaps Eleanor as child."
  - #10 / New #8 (Offsite-box 11, Reel -)
    Written on bottom of can: "Old pictures, Cornell-Pa game, 1933, [caponizing hens?], Lake Placid, 1933."
  - #9 / New #9 (Offsite-box 11, Reel -)
    Written on bottom of can: "Fire Island, July 1932; Jones Beach, Gill Haig, Johnny, Placid."
  - #11 / New #10 (Offsite-box 11, Reel -)
    Written on can: "Feb 10, 1935: Miami, Coral Gables, [3 other words]". "[word?] Century, Arthur, Jesse, [word?], MSF: 1934." "Martin Erdmar, 1936." "Johnny @ Bermuda, 1936; Albert Hellers [word?] 1936."
  - #15 / New #12 (Offsite-box 12, Reel -)
    Original handwriting on bottom of can: Eleanor's [honey?]moon, Mildred's graduation, Johnny flying: 1933"; "[Tex?] OK 1948." Modern tape: "1. Joe & Eleanor leaving on boat for honeymoon?, 2. Mildred's graduating, 3. Construction? 4. NY family: Joe, Eleanor, Mildred, Grandpa, Uncle George P. Andrea [?] Einstein. Mike 5/15/14"
  - #13 / New #16 (Offsite-box 12, Reel -)
    Written on can: "Johnny's wedding trip, 1935. Italy, Berlin." On white leader on reel marked: "MSF & PB Wedding Trip (No USSR)."
  - #17 / New #14 (Offsite-box 12, Reel -)
    Written on bottom of can (over "Rio" and other words): "Mildred Wedding, July 11, '39." Also labeled on such on reel.
  - #12 / New #15 (Offsite-box 12, Reel -)
    Original handwriting on bottom of can cannot be read. Original tape around can: "Pat & Bobby." On top of can: "Baby Pat & Bobby." On reel: "Baby Pat & Robert."
  - #13 / New #16 (Offsite-box 12, Reel -)
    No can. No subject label on reel. Notes from donor indicate this reel includes "Kids '38 & '39."
  - #14 / New #17 (Offsite-box 12, Reel -)
    Original handwriting on bottom of can: "[2 words?], Taormina[?], Pompeii[?]" Modern tape: "Pat & Bobby, 1941." On white leader of film: "Bobby & Pat, 1941?"
  - #18 / New #19 (Offsite-box 12, Reel -)
    Written on bottom of can: "Europe 1952." Written on reel: "Children in Europe.'
  - #19 / New #20 (Offsite-box 12, Reel -)
    Written on bottom of can: "Europe, Johnny, II." Written on top of can: "Europe." Written on reel: "Europe, 1934 [overwritten to be 1930?], MSF Jr."
  - #2 / New #1 (Offsite-box 10, Reel -)
    No original can. White leader on film: "Sports & family, Portchester, 1924?"
  - #3 / New #11 (Offsite-box 10, Reel -)
    Film in deteriorated condition. Written on reel: "Wedding trip, 1935, Italy & Berlin." Written on tape on reel: "Lake Placid." Written on Post-it: "Could be Portchester, 1920s/1924, Lake Placid, year?"
  - #31 / No new # (2 reels) (Offsite-box 10, Reel -)
    No original cans. Two reels. Card describes as "Paris/Bremen/Berlin, 1931?"
  - #? / New #18 (Offsite-box 10, Reel -)
    No original can. On white leader of film: "Color, 66th Street, B-Day/Portchester, 1941/Elberon 1942."
  - No numbers, 1943 (Offsite-box 12, Reel -)
    Small reel in box labeled as from Edgar Loew for development, subject "Alison at farm." DVD of the film has Post-it label "Mildred Falk Loew and Alison Loew, Summer 1943, Top Hill Farm, Port Chester.
  - 14 DVDs and 1 USB Drive (RESTRICTED), 1920s-1950s (Offsite-box 5, Folder 10)
    Digitized versions of at least some of the film, provided by the donor. These versions include the film of Falk's travels and home movies. These discs are restricted from use. However the contents were copied to N-YHS's network. For access to the files, contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org.
  - Notes and labels removed from film cans (Offsite-box 5, Folder 11)